# P.O Box 14521-00100

# Nairobi, Kenya 0700699383

### Lucythairu42@gmail.com

#### **SUMMARY**

Motivated soon to be graduated in August 2023 having finished my studies in August 2022. Possesses problem solving abilities, team oriented and ability to work well in a collaborative environment. Being able to learn new information quickly to maximize contributions and respond to the customers preference and managerial preference. Proficient in flexibility and adaptation and willing to further my experience and excel in the field of Travel and Tourism to meet organizational objectives.

#### **EDUCATION**

#### [2019-2022] BACHELOR OF SCIENCE IN TRAVEL AND TOURISM MANAGEMENT, MOUNT KENYA UNIVERSITY

- Behavioral Science
- Project Planning and Management
- Introduction to Hospitality and Tourism
- Flora and Fauna of East Africa
- World Geography and Touristic Destination
- Tour Operations
- Survival Techniques in Tourism
- Photography and Documentary in Tourism
- Communication skills
- Principles of Management
- Travel Agency Operation
- Front office Operation 1 and 2
- Domestic and International Tourism
- Tourism Product Development
- Financial Accounting in Hospitality and Tourism
- Research Methodology
- Human Resource Management
- Marketing for Hospitality and Tourism management
- Management Information system
- Coastal and Marine Tourism Management
- Tourism and Hospitality Economics
- Crisis Management in Travel and Tourism
- Events Management
- Sustainable Tourism Management

- Business statistics 1
- Financial management in Hospitality and Tourism
- Service Quality Management
- Wildlife Conservation Management
- Sports, Leisure and Recreation
- Tourism Planning and Policy
- Cultural Heritage Tourism
- Destination Management
- Legal aspects in Hospitality and Tourism
- Entrepreneurship
- Final project year

#### [2017-2018] DIPLOMA IN TOURISM MANAGEMENT, ZETECH UNIVERSITY

- Service Operations Management
- Tourism Project Management
- Airline ticketing
- Public relations in Tourism
- Information Communication Technology
- Airline Booking system

#### [2016-2017] CERTIFICATE IN HOSPITALITY AND TOURISM MANAGEMENT, ZETECH UNIVERSITY

- Food Production Theory
- Introduction to Tours and Travel Operations
- Food Production Practical
- Food Service Theory
- Food and Beverage control
- Food Services Practical
- IT in Travel, Tourism and Hospitality

[2012-2015] KENYA CERTIFICATE OF SECONDAY EDUCATION, MOI GIRLS SECONDARY SCHOOL [2001-2011] KENYA CERTIFICATE OF PRIMARY EDUCATION, TUMAINI SPIRE JUNIOR SCHOOL

#### **SOCIAL ACTIVITIES**

- Involvement in the Kenya Society for the blind 2016
- Involvement in History makers 2012
- Participating in youth competition activities

#### **SKILLS**

**Teamwork:** My roles have acquired me to work with different number of people together and help each other to ensure successful events, which have given me experience in working with different people and the teams involved.

**Presentation:** To bring pass my ideas on school diploma project I have undertaken and I have frequently required to deliver presentations to groups of people and my presentations have been effective in achieving this goal.

**Communication and Interpersonal skills**: Having managed to undertake my certificate, diploma and degree course involving my proposal and project presentation, my communication and interpersonal skills are excellent.

#### **HOBBIES**

- Travelling
- Playing Badminton
- Swimming

#### **EMPLOYMENT HISTORY**

#### [Jan 2022 – PRESENT] Business Woman, Wakindu Guest house & Cafe

## [February 2020 – March 2020] DATA ENTRY, Africa Vocational Education Researchers and Consultants (AVERC)

- Correctly and accurately converted physical information to digital data
- Analyzed the physical data and spotted the mistakes
- Updated already existing digital data with new data
- Gave feedback on any broken data or missing data
- Ensured all the data is up to date

#### [August 2022 - December 2022] ATTACHEE, Ministry of Tourism

#### [May 2018 - August 2018] Jambo Travel House Limited

- Handling Bookings of client
- Putting holiday packages together
- Picking up clients at airports
- Invoicing tickets

#### **LANGUAGES SPOKEN**

ENGLISH

Spoken (Fluently)

Written (Fluently)

KISWAHILI

Spoken (Fluently)

Written (Fluently)

#### **PORTFOLIO**

Here is a link to my portfolio for your perusal:

Lucythairu.vercel.app

#### **REFEREES**

Ian Ray Kimathi

Email: kagunyaian@gmail.com

Tel: 0743845711
Locale: Nairobi

Joseph Hinga

Email: hingandumbi@gmail.com

Tel: 0715587016
Locale: Nairobi
• Faith Bichachi

Email: bichachinekesa@gmail.com

**Tel:** 0714275552

**Alt Tel:** 0787652832

Locale: Nairobi